KittaChat is a full-stack realtime communication platform
for direct messages and group collaboration.
It also supports shared files, presence,
and peer-to-peer audio and video calls.
In direct chat, Alice sees her message immediately
through optimistic UI.
The client preserves a generated idempotency key
across network retries.
MongoDB safely upserts the message
by sender and idempotency key.
Bob receives the persisted message in realtime,
even through another backend replica.
Delivery stays responsive without claiming
exactly-once semantics.
The sidebar reacts to incoming activity
without a page refresh.
Sam's message increments unread state
and moves the conversation upward.
Filter-specific cursor pagination keeps
direct and group views independent.
Infinite scroll loads older conversations
without losing the active selection.
Batch enrichment avoids per-conversation lookups
as the unified list grows.
Group collaboration preserves sender identity
across every member's view.
Bob's message appears with the correct author
and updates connected members through Socket.IO.
The Redis Adapter carries room events
across three Express replicas behind nginx.
Realtime delivery is not limited to users
connected to the same backend process.
The Conversation Information Panel brings
shared context into one place.
It presents metadata, members, shared media,
files, and links.
Each View All explorer owns its cursor
and infinite-scroll state.
Freshness banners announce new resources
without disrupting the current snapshot.
The media lightbox keeps focused browsing
separate from the underlying conversation.
The panel becomes a shared-resource workspace,
not only a settings drawer.
Calls use Socket.IO only for signaling.
After Bob accepts, WebRTC carries audio and video
directly between the peers.
Media controls update during the call.
A MongoDB-gated finalizer protects the main
termination paths from conflicting call history.
KittaChat combines three Socket.IO replicas,
Redis coordination, RabbitMQ workers, and MongoDB.
Its engineering story starts with cross-replica delivery
and retry-safe message persistence.
It also covers gated call finalization,
a scalable sidebar, and resilient background jobs.
Tests, builds, source code, and design documents
are linked directly from the repository.